Huh?
啊？
Intruders.
入侵者。
A break-in.
闯入。
I knew this can of hairspray
would come in handy one day.
我知道这罐发胶
有一天会派上用场的。
Who's down there?
谁在下面？
I have an aerosol can and
I'm not afraid to use it.
我有一个气雾罐并且
我并不害怕使用它。
My eyes.
我的眼睛。
Huh?
Happy friend-i...
啊？
快乐的朋友-我...
Happy friend-iversary,
Squidward!
朋友结婚纪念日快乐，
章鱼哥！
SpongeBob, what time is it?
海绵宝宝，现在几点了？
It's one minute
after midnight
这是一分钟
午夜之后
on the day
that we first met.
当天
我们第一次见面。
It's all here in
my Squidward memory book.
一切都在这里
我的《章鱼哥》记忆册。
- What?
- Here's us at camp.
- 什么？
- 这是我们在营地。
Here's when I moved in
right next door.
这是我搬进来的时候
就在隔壁。
Oh, and here's when I got
哦，这时我得到了
employee of the month
instead of you again.
本月最佳员工
再次代替你。
Here's one I took
a few minutes ago.
这是我拍的一张
几分钟前。
Look at you.
Just like an angel.
看看你。
就像天使一样。
All right, that's it.
好吧，就是这样。
Get out.
出去。
Okay, see you around, friend.
好的，再见，朋友。
♪ Friend, friend, friend,
friend, friend ♪
♪ 朋友，朋友，朋友，
朋友，朋友♪
♪ Friend, friend, friend,
friend, friend, friend ♪
♪ 朋友，朋友，朋友，
朋友，朋友，朋友♪
♪ Friend, friend-iversary ♪
♪ 朋友，朋友纪念日 ♪
Happy friend-iversary!
朋友周年快乐！
Remember the first time
记得第一次
I startled you
into this trash can?
我吓到你了
扔进这个垃圾桶？
Ah, go away. Go away.
啊，走开。离开。
Classic, Squiddy.
经典，鱿鱼。
Memories.
回忆。
Is he here?
他在吗？
Not here.
不在这里。
Hey, Squidward!
嘿，章鱼哥！
Remember that time
I dedicated a song to you?
还记得那个时候
我献给你一首歌？
Oh, you do remember.
哦，你还记得。
Leave me be.
别管我了。
Remember the time
I got you these rocket skates?
记住时间
我给你买了这双火箭溜冰鞋？
Uh, no.
呃，不。
That's because we're making
a new memory.
那是因为我们正在做
一个新的记忆。
- No.
- Happy friend-iversary.
- 不。
- 朋友纪念日快乐。
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Oh, the Kelpie G concert.
哦，Kelpie G 演唱会。
Now, that was a good memory.
现在看来，那是一段美好的回忆。
Huh.
呵呵。
Huh?
"Remember this, Squidward?"
啊？
“还记得这个吗，章鱼哥？”
Happy friend-iversary.
朋友纪念日快乐。
Huh?
- Remember this, Squidward?
啊？
- 还记得这个吗，章鱼哥？
Huh?
啊？
Remember this, Squidward?
还记得这个吗，章鱼哥？
Please, you got to help me.
拜托，你一定要帮助我。
Remember this, Squidward?
还记得这个吗，章鱼哥？
Oh, no. Not you. No, no.
哦，不。不是你。不，不。
Friend-iversary.
朋友纪念日。
Happy friend-iversary.
朋友周年快乐。
He remembers everything.
他记得一切。
Everything that happened.
所发生的一切。
Even things that didn't happen.
即使没有发生的事情。
Maybe even things
that will happen.
甚至可能是一些事情
那将会发生。
Things that will never happen.
永远不会发生的事情。
If he remembers it, it happens.
如果他记得的话，就会发生。
Get ahold of yourself, Squidward.
控制住自己，章鱼哥。
There's got to be a way out.
必须有一条出路。
There's got to be
a way to erase...
一定有
一种擦除...的方法
An eraser.
一块橡皮。
I'll erase his memories of me.
我会抹去他对我的记忆。
There's only one more place
he keeps his memories.
只剩下一个地方了
他保留着他的记忆。
Erase me. Erase me.
抹掉我吧抹掉我吧
Oh, Squidward,
let's be roommates
哦，章鱼哥，
我们做室友吧
and live together forever
and ever and ever.
并永远生活在一起
永远永远。
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Good morning.
- Oh, good morning.
早上好。
- 哦，早上好。
You must be the new cashier.
Nice to meet you.
你一定是新来的收银员。
很高兴见到你。
I can't believe it.
It worked.
我简直不敢相信。
它起作用了。
Uh, have we met before?
呃，我们以前见过吗？
I don't think so.
Maybe we can chat later, huh?
我不这么认为。
也许我们可以稍后再聊，嗯？
I'm kind of busy right now.
我现在有点忙。
This is the best day
of my life.
这是最好的一天
我的生活。
Hmm, you seem weirdly happy
for some reason.
嗯，你看起来很高兴
由于某种原因。
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Last night, I erased all of
SpongeBob's memories of me.
昨晚我把所有的都删掉了
海绵宝宝对我的回忆。
Isn't that wonderful?
那不是很棒吗？
You what?
你什么？
Are you insane, man?
你疯了吗，伙计？
To keep Plankton from
scanning me mind,
为了防止浮游生物
扫描我的脑海，
SpongeBob is the only one
who knows the combination
海绵宝宝是唯一的一个
谁知道组合
to the secret formula safe.
以秘密配方安全。
And because he never wanted
to forget it,
因为他从来不想
忘记它，
ha attached it to a memory he
had with you, Mr. Squidward.
哈哈把它附加到他的记忆中
和你在一起了，章鱼哥先生。
I want you to un-erase
his memory right now.
我要你取消删除
他现在的记忆。
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
Yes, Mr. Krabs.
是的，蟹老板。
Spend the afternoon with
Mr. Squidward here.
度过一个下午
章鱼哥先生在这里。
He's gonna share some
precious memories with you.
他会分享一些
和你在一起的珍贵回忆。
Oh, no thank you.
I don't know this guy.
哦，不，谢谢。
我不认识这个人。
He's a stranger.
他是个陌生人。
Confidentially,
he looks a little boring.
秘密地说，
他看起来有点无聊。
You go with him.
That's an order.
你和他一起去吧。
这是命令。
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
So what are we doing now,
new guy?
那么我们现在在做什么
新人？
We're going to recreate
your lost memories of me,
我们要重新创建
你对我失去的记忆
so you can remember the
combination of Krabs' safe.
这样你就可以记住
螃蟹保险箱的组合。
Huh, sounds crazy-pants,
but okay.
嗯，听起来很疯狂，
但好吧。
Just do what I tell you.
照我说的做就行了。
- Hmm?
- Mm-mm.
- 唔？
- 嗯嗯。
Mm-mm.
嗯嗯。
Huh?
啊？
Mm-mm.
嗯嗯。
Hmm, mm-mm.
嗯，嗯嗯。
Meh.
嗯。
All right, if this doesn't
make you remember me
好吧，如果这没有
让你记住我
then nothing will.
那么什么都不会。
Nope, it's just
not ringing a...
不，这只是
不响...
Squidward.
章鱼哥。
Squidward, I remember this.
I remember you.
章鱼哥，我记得这个。
我记得你。
I remember the combination
to the safe.
我记得组合
到保险箱。
Hooray, hooray.
Hooray-ay-ay.
万岁，万岁。
万岁，哎呀。
Yeah, that's great.
Just stop shaking the...
是的，那太好了。
只要停止摇晃...
The combination is
three impacts to the right.
组合是
向右三个冲击。
No, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不。
My body.
- Five punchings to the left.
我的身体。
- 向左打五拳。
Six stretched limbs
to the right.
六肢伸展
到右边。
And 56 school children
to the left.
还有56名小学生
到左边。
No, wait. That's not it.
不，等等。不是这个。
Oh, 57.
哦，57。
Oh, Squidward, I remember.
I remember.
噢，章鱼哥，我记得。
我记得。
You know, Squidward, there's
something else I remembered.
你知道，章鱼哥，有
我还记得别的事。
Yesterday wasn't
our friend-iversary.
昨天不是
我们的朋友纪念日。
It's today!
- No.
就在今天！
- 不。
No. No!
不，不！
Happy friend-iversary.
朋友纪念日快乐。
Or is it tomorrow?
还是明天？